<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-27T21:57:07+04:00</updated><id>https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Musings on Maps</title><subtitle>A blog made for my 2018 Data and Human Space class.</subtitle><author><name>Benjamin Pang</name></author><entry><title type="html">Reflection: Torn Apart/Separados</title><link href="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/25/project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection: Torn Apart/Separados" /><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/25/project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/25/project.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://xpmethod.plaintext.in/torn-apart/volume/2/index&quot;&gt;Torn Apart/Separados&lt;/a&gt; is a project that aims to reveal the deep web of corporate connections that the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) has built. From data collected between 2014 to 2018 about corporation-ICE contracts, a team of scholars and activists have created a variety of vivid visualizations depicting various aspects of ICE’s convoluted infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/assets/torn-apart.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/assets/torn-apart-rain.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/assets/torn-apart-bar.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/assets/torn-apart-web.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first visualization you are presented with when viewing the project is a map of the US, with each district colored depending on the amount of funding awarded by ICE. Hovering your cursor over a district will reveal more information about that district’s funding situation; for example, my home district – California’s 14th District – has received $140,000 from ICE, with an image-processing company called MotionDSP receiving $100,000 of that funding. Other visualizations include a rain chart showing the significant increase in money and amount of ICE contracts given out from 2014 to 2018, a bar chart showing the amount of money given by ICE to minority-owned businesses, and a web showing the complex interactions between companies involved with ICE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these visualizations do reveal the absurdity of ICE’s whole operation. The amount of money spent on corporate contracts along with the tangled mess of interactions between the involved companies just goes to show the impracticality and waste of time that immigrant deportation has brought. Perhaps equally concerning are the types of companies involved: universities, media companies, tech companies, and websites. Many of the contracted entities are brands and names that many of us would label as respectable or morally righteous (ex.: Dell, Amazon, LinkedIn, Johns Hopkins) – and yet those same companies are complicit in the displacement of hundreds of thousands of illegal immigrants every year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Pang</name></author><summary type="html">Torn Apart/Separados is a project that aims to reveal the deep web of corporate connections that the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) has built. From data collected between 2014 to 2018 about corporation-ICE contracts, a team of scholars and activists have created a variety of vivid visualizations depicting various aspects of ICE’s convoluted infrastructure.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spatial Perspectives</title><link href="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/04/spatial-perspectives.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spatial Perspectives" /><published>2018-10-04T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-10-04T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/04/spatial-perspectives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/04/spatial-perspectives.html">&lt;p&gt;When I was a middle-schooler, I came up with the idea to create miniscule trackers that I could stick onto any of my belongings and track from my phone or computer. In 2018, this idea sounds rather easy to implement. But back then, the iPhone 5 and Samsung Galaxy S3 had just been released. “4G” stood for “prohibitively expensive” and unlimited data plans were unheard of. Few app developers cared about “Location Services” and even fewer cared to integrate it into their apps. Most importantly, I didn’t even have a phone to track anything with. All of these limitations forced me to put off my idea until years later, when I began attending hackathons as a high-schooler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my entry into middle school to my graduation from high school, the little-used Location Services has gradually become a regular fixture in our digital lives; in 2016, the Pew Research Institute found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2016/01/29/us-smartphone-use/&quot;&gt;9 out of 10 American smartphone owners used their phone for location-based information&lt;/a&gt;. Almost all apps gather location-based data, directly or indirectly. A standard navigation app like Google Maps or Waze is able to gather real-time data about traffic, weather, hidden routes, etc. to find an optimal path from point A to point B. Other apps use location data to suggest points of interest in the area, create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pokemongo.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;more immersive gaming experience&lt;/a&gt;, or simply help with tagging photos on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the near-ubiquitous gathering of location data also makes it much easier for our privacy to be breached. Location Services has given everyone access to our location, from massive corporations to small-time programming hobbyists. Unfortunately, “everyone” includes people who can abuse such data: hackers, pranksters, greedy companies. Even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/-trackmageddon-vulnerabilities-discovered-in-gps-location-tracking-services/&quot;&gt;vulnerabilities in GPS services&lt;/a&gt; could indirectly leak your location data to the world. Even if Location Services is turned off, websites are still able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iplocation.net&quot;&gt;deduce your general location from your IP address&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it interesting that the improvement in location data collection has completely overturned the way we view privacy. There is a point in time at which each smartphone owner will have to consider whether the benefits of giving an unknown entity your location outweigh the drawbacks of giving an unknown entity your privacy. Luckily, VPNs, proxies, TOR, and other privacy-oriented technologies can mask your location and identity online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually… I take that back. Even the US government can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/secret-nsa-documents-show-campaign-against-tor-encrypted-network/2013/10/04/610f08b6-2d05-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html?utm_term=.f4a3b69f878e&quot;&gt;hack TOR&lt;/a&gt; and have almost singlehandedly &lt;a href=&quot;https://surveillancevalley.com/blog/fact-checking-the-tor-projects-government-ties&quot;&gt;funded TOR too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Pang</name></author><summary type="html">When I was a middle-schooler, I came up with the idea to create miniscule trackers that I could stick onto any of my belongings and track from my phone or computer. In 2018, this idea sounds rather easy to implement. But back then, the iPhone 5 and Samsung Galaxy S3 had just been released. “4G” stood for “prohibitively expensive” and unlimited data plans were unheard of. Few app developers cared about “Location Services” and even fewer cared to integrate it into their apps. Most importantly, I didn’t even have a phone to track anything with. All of these limitations forced me to put off my idea until years later, when I began attending hackathons as a high-schooler.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post!</title><link href="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/02/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post!" /><published>2018-10-02T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/02/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dhs.bennyboy.hosting.nyu.edu/2018/10/02/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benjamin Pang</name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to my blog!</summary></entry></feed>